Register to the Papers of Vladimir and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz
Yale University Music Library
The Papers of Vladimir and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz.
1784-1991
MSS 55
Yale University Music Library
69
(164 boxes)
Correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the Russian-American pianist Vladimir Horowitz (1903-1989) and his wife Wanda Toscanini Horowitz (1907-1998)
Horowitz, Vladimir, 1903-1989
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to qualified researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Papers of Vladimir and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz are the generous gift of Mr. and Mrs. Horowitz. The collection was presented to the Music Library in twelve installments from 1986 to 1992.
Arrangement
In 9 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Programs and Program Notes. III. Photographs. IV. Clippings. V. Scrapbooks. VI. Contracts, Royalty and Box Office Statements, Expenses. VII. Items from the Library of Vladimir Horowitz. VIII. Awards. IX. Miscellaneous Items.
Scope and Contents
The Papers of Vladimir Horowitz and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz (1784-1991) reflect the life and work of the legendary pianist, Vladimir Horowitz, and of his wife, Wanda Toscanini Horowitz. The Papers chronicle Horowitz's life and illustrious seventy-one year career from Kiev to New York.
The Papers include correspondence, programs, photographs, clippings, scrapbooks, contracts, royalty statements, awards, certificates, jewelry, and a wide range of memorabilia. Included too are manuscript and published music, autograph letters of famous composers, and original works of art from the Horowitzes' private collection. The Papers document the Horowitzes' close association with such figures as Sergei Rachmaninoff, Rudolf Serkin, Arthur Rubinstein, Nathan Milstein, Gregor Piatigorsky, Olin Downes, Isaac Stern, Arturo Toscanini, and Bruno Walter. The music includes holograph manuscripts of works by Horowitz, Poulenc, and Prokofiev. There is also much published music with markings by Horowitz and/or inscriptions from composers and friends.
Very important are the 218 unpublished live recordings on acetate disc of Horowitz's Carnegie Hall recitals of the 1940s and 50s. Horowitz had these 12 and 16 inch discs made for personal use. They are cataloged and housed at Yale University's Historical Sound Recordings Collection, where they have been copied unto tape for preservation purposes and are available for researchers. Mrs. Horowitz also donated a treasure of items pertaining to her father, Arturo Toscanini. These include many photographs, scrapbooks, correspondence, and memorabilia. There are also 324 recordings by Toscanini or Toscanini and Horowitz made by the Franklin Mint Society, Musica Amica, RCA Artistique, RCA Camden, RCA Victor/Red Seal, RCA Victrola, RCA Victrola (Italy), RCA Victor-Japan, and Columbia. These are also housed and cataloged at Yale University's Historical Sound Recordings Collection.
Biographical / Historical
Vladimir Horowitz (in Russian, Gorowitz) was born in Berdichev, near Kiev, on October 1, 1903. His father, Simeon, was an electrical engineer, and his mother, Sophie, a pianist. It was Sophie who gave Volodya (as he was affectionately called), his sister, Regina, and brothers Jacob and George, their first music lessons. When he was ten years old, Horowitz entered the Kiev Conservatory where he studied with Vladimir Puchalsky, Sergei Tarnowsky, and Felix Blumenfeld.
At first, Horowitz aspired to be a composer, and as a teenager produced several compositions (the holograph manuscript of one of these works, Etude-fantasie es-dur op. 4: Les Vagues (dedicated to Tarnovsky), is among the Papers). But revolution and the hardships of life under the Bolsheviks intervened, forcing him to abandon his dream of becoming a composer (his dazzling piano transcriptions written later in his career attest to his compositional talents). With his father's successful business and most of their possessions, including the piano, seized by the Bolsheviks, and the Horowitzes living together with all of their relatives in poverty, Vladimir Horowitz was determined to use his phenomenal talent as a pianist to help his family. He graduated from the Conservatory in 1920, giving his first public performance in Kiev on May 30 of that year. His paternal uncle Alexander, a pupil of Scriabin, became his first manager. In 1922, Uncle Alexander was replaced as manager by the state, which then dictated the careers of Horowitz, his sister, and his good friend Nathan Milstein. From 1922 to 1925 he performed extensively in Kharkov, Kiev, Moscow, and Leningrad, and his reputation as a virtuoso grew.
After state management, Horowitz's career was overseen by Alexander Merovitch, who helped Horowitz leave Russia in 1925. The decision to leave was difficult, and the only family member he was to ever see again was his father, once, in 1934. His first performance outside of Russia was in Berlin, on January 2, 1926. From 1926 to 1927 he gave sixty-nine concerts throughout Europe, and became immensely popular with the public. He studied briefly with Alfred Cortot in Paris, in 1928. Horowitz switched management to Arthur Judson, and on January 12, 1928, made his American debut with Sir Thomas Beecham and the New York Philharmonic playing Tchaikovsky's First Piano Concerto. His debut was sensational; the audience was amazed by his performance. Horowitz's career took off: he performed for sold-out concerts, commanded the highest fees, and became universally celebrated. In 1933 Mr. Horowitz performed Beethoven's Emperor Concerto with Toscanini and the New York Philharmonic as part of a Beethoven cycle. The concert was a great success, and he won the admiration of Toscanini, whose daughter, Wanda, he married on December 21, 1933, in Milan. Their daughter, Sonia, was born in 1934.
The Horowitzes came to the United States in 1939, and he became a citizen in 1942. He gave the world premiere of Samuel Barber's Piano Sonata on December 9, 1949, in Havana. Horowitz began a twelve-year retirement from concert life after his Silver Jubilee concert on February 25, 1953, during which time he made a few recordings. Horowitz made his triumphant return to the concert stage at Carnegie Hall on May 9, 1965. Throngs of eager fans stood in the ticket line overnight, and the tickets were sold out in two hours.
Horowitz's televised recital in September 1968 was a huge success, allowing viewers across the country to see him in performance. After a retirement from 1969 to 1974, during which Horowitz made and reissued recordings, he gave the first piano recital at the new Metropolitan Opera House on November 17, 1974. On January 8, 1978, he celebrated the fiftieth anniversary of his American debut at Carnegie Hall playing Rachmaninoff's Concerto No. 3 with Eugene Ormandy and the New York Philharmonic. He performed in Europe for the first time in thirty-one years in a recital in London's Royal Festival Hall on May 22, 1982, and he played a series of recitals for the first time in Japan in 1983. In the following years he toured Europe and Japan, performed in the United States, and made recordings, videos, telecasts, and films. Horowitz made an historic return to the Soviet Union after a sixty-one year absence in 1986, and for this was later awarded the United States Presidential Medal of Freedom by President Reagan.
Horowitz performed at the White House for Presidents Hoover, Carter, and Reagan. President Bush bestowed upon him the National Medal of Arts in 1989.
On November 1, 1989, Horowitz made what was to be The Last Recording. He died suddenly, on November 5, 1989, of a heart attack. After the funeral in New York, his body was flown to Milan where he was buried in the Toscanini family plot.
Vladimir and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz papers; Beatrix, Queen of the Netherlands, 1938-; Abbado, Claudio, 1933-2014; Albanese, Licia, 1909-2014; Alda, Frances, 1883-1952; Allen, Betty, 1927-2009; Allen, Woody, 1935-; Anderson, Marian, 1897-1993; Andreae, Volkmar, 1879-1962; Argerich, Martha, 1941-; Arrau, Claudio, 1903-1991; Ashkenazy, Vladimir, 1937-; Babin, Victor, 1908-1972; Bachauer, Gina, 1910-1976; Badura-Skoda, Paul, 1927-; Bakaleinikoff, Vladimir, 1885-1953; Bampton, Rose; Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981; Bergonzi, Carlo, 1924-2014; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990; Bliss, Arthur, 1891-1975; Bolet, Jorge, 1914-1990; Bookspan, Martin; Bori, Lucrezia, 1887-1960; Boulez, Pierre, 1925-2016; Browning, John, 1933-2003; Buckley, William F., Jr., 1925-2008; Burkat, Leonard, 1919-1992; Busch, Adolf, 1891-1952; Calligaris, Sergio, 1941-; Carlisle, Kitty, 1910-2007; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Casadesus, Gaby; Casadesus, Marius; Casella, Alfredo, 1883-1947; Ceccato, Aldo; Chamberlain, Houston Stewart, 1855-1927; Chapin, Schuyler, 1923-2009; Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987; Cherkassky, Shura, 1909-1995; Cliburn, Van, 1934-2013; Collard, Jean-Philippe, 1948-; Comden, Betty, 1919-2006; Corigliano, John, 1938-; Davis, Andrew, 1944-; Davis, Ivan, 1932-; Diamond, David, 1915-2005; Dietrich, Marlene, 1901-1992; Downes, Olin, 1886-1955; Eschenbach, Christoph, 1940-; Farrow, Mia, 1945-; Feltsman, Vladimir, 1952-; Firkušný, Rudolf, 1912-1994; Foster, Sidney; Freccia, Massimo, 1906-2004; Freundlich, Irwin; Friedberg, Carl, 1872-1955; Ganz, Rudolph, 1877-1972; Garbousova, Raya, 1905-1997; Gavazzeni, Gianandrea, 1909-1996; Gavoty, Bernard, 1908-1981; Gilels, Emil, 1916-1985; Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938; Golschmann, Vladimir, 1893-1972; Gould, Morton, 1913-1996; Graffman, Gary, 1928-; Gregorian, Vartan; Haas, Karl; Hedley, Arthur, 1905-1969; Heifetz, Jascha, 1901-1987; Henderson, Skitch, 1918-2005; Hendl, Walter, 1917-2007; Hofmann, Josef, 1876-1957; Horne, Marilyn, 1934-; Horowitz, Vladimir, 1903-1989; Horowitz, Wanda Toscanini; Horszowski, Mieczyslaw, 1892-1993; Hume, Paul, 1915-2001; Hurok, Sol, 1888-1974; Istomin, Eugene, 1925-2001; Iturbi, José, 1895-1980; Janis, Byron, 1928-; Johannesen, Grant, 1921-2005; Judson, Arthur, 1881-1975; Kallir, Lilian; Karajan, Herbert von, 1908-1989; Keene, Constance; Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), 1932-2009; Kennedy, Ethel, 1928-; Kennedy, Rose Fitzgerald, 1890-1995; King, Coretta Scott, 1927-2006; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Kipnis, Igor; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Koch, Ed, 1924-2013; Kolodin, Irving, 1908-1988; Kostelanetz, Andre, 1901-1980; Koussevitzky, Olga; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962; Lambro, Phillip, 1935-; Larrocha, Alicia de; Lateiner, Jacob, 1928-2010; Leinsdorf, Erich, 1912-1993; Levant, Oscar, 1906-1972; Levine, James, 1943-; Lewenthal, Raymond, 1926-1988; Lieberson, Goddard, 1911-1977; Lifar, Serge, 1905-1986; List, Eugene, 1918-1985; London, George, 1920-1985; Lualdi, Adriano, 1885-1971; Lympany, Moura, 1916-2005; Maazel, Lorin, 1930-2014; Machlis, Joseph, 1906-1998; Małcużyński, Witold, 1914-1977; Maynor, Dorothy; Mehta, Zubin, 1936-; Mennin, Peter, 1923-1983; Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911-2007; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999; Milstein, Nathan, 1903-1992; Mitropoulos, Dimitri, 1896-1960; Mondale, Walter F., 1928-; Montgomery, Merle, 1904-1986; Moynihan, Daniel P. (Daniel Patrick), 1927-2003; Munch, Charles, 1891-1968; Nabokov, Nicolas, 1903-1978; Nero, Peter, 1934-; Newman, Ernest, 1868-1959; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985; Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941; Pavarotti, Luciano, 1935-2007; Pelletier, Wilfrid, 1896-1982; Perahia, Murray, 1947-; Perlman, Itzhak, 1945-; Piatigorsky, Gregor, 1903-1976; Pizzetti, Ildebrando, 1880-1968; Polignac, Winnaretta, princesse de, 1865-1943; Pollini, Maurizio, 1942-; Ponselle, Rosa, 1897-1981; Price, Leontyne, 1927-; Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943; Ramey, Phillip, 1939-; Randall, Tony, 1920-2004; Reagan, Ronald, 1911-2004; Reisenberg, Nadia, 1904-1983; Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936; Richter, Sviatoslav, 1915-1997; Rostropovich, Mstislav, 1927-2007; Rubinstein, Artur, 1887-1982; Schneider, Alexander, 1908-1993; Schonberg, Harold C., 1915-2003; Serkin, Peter, 1947-; Serkin, Rudolf, 1903-1991; Shalit, Gene, 1936-; Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975; Siegel, Jeffrey; Simon, Abbey; Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995; Smit, Leo, 1921-1999; Solti, Georg, 1912-1997; Spivakov, Vladimir, 1944-; Steinberg, William, 1899-1978; Stern, Isaac, 1920-2001; Stevens, Risë, 1913-2013; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Stravinsky, Soulima, 1910-1994; Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957; Tourel, Jennie, 1900-1973; Trudeau, Pierre Elliott, 1919-2000; Turchi, Guido, 1916-2010; Tureck, Rosalyn, 1914-2003; Visconti, Luchino, 1906-1976; Voxman, Himie; Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012; Wallenstein, Alfred, 1898-1983; Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962; Walters, Barbara, 1929-; Weissenberg, Alexis, 1929-2012; Zecchi, Carlo, 1903-1984; Zeltser, Mark, 1947-; Zweig, Stefan, 1881-1942; Steinway & Sons
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1890-1991; Series I; 32 boxes (13.3')
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence is divided into two subseries: A. Personal; and B. By Subject. The personal correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender then chronologically. Copies and drafts of letters from Horowitz are filed with the recipient's correspondence and a note has been made in the register. Replies made in behalf of Horowitz by others such as Harold Shaw, Peter Gelb, and secretaries, are filed under Horowitz. This series includes correspondence to and from Vladimir Horowitz and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz, as well as from Sonia Horowitz, and to and from Arturo Toscanini. Original correspondence from Vladimir Horowitz to Wanda Toscanini Horowitz and Arturo Toscanini, and from Sonia Horowitz to Arturo Toscanini are listed under the authors' names. The correspondence in the second subseries is grouped by subject and listed chronologically with a chronological arrangement within each group. Fan mail is included in this subseries.
  Originals of letters from important people which were found grouped by subject are now filed with personal correspondence and photocopies of these remain in subseries B, VI. CONTRACTS, and IX. MISCELLANEOUS ITEMS - Items pertaining to Toscanini.
  Enclosures are noted and counted in the items column.
  Cross-references have been made between individuals with correspondence in both subseries as well as between series. For instance, cross-references have been made between correspondence in series VI. CONTRACTS... and I.A. Personal Correspondence. There are also cross-references from various forms of names to the main entries.
  The entries under Arturo Toscanini, in I.A., include correspondence to and from Toscanini. The correspondence from Toscanini to his family is followed by correspondence to others, which includes photocopies of correspondence from other important people (the originals are at the New York Public Library).
  A pencil note appears on the item or its folder for correspondence originally found in another series such as V. SCRAPBOOKS (which have been microfilmed and disassembled).
  Drafts of letters on legal paper and paper in poor condition have been copied onto acid-free paper.
  There is one oversize box (132) for correspondence which is housed at the end with other oversize boxes.
  - CORRESPONDENCE - Personal, I.A
    - ARTEC, ca. 1989 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aaron, Judith
      General
      See: Carnegie Hall Corporation
    - Aaron Richmond Concerts, Inc.
      See: Richmond, Aaron
    - Abbado, Claudio, 1987 May 30; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes 1 phone message
    - Abrams, Steve, 1967 Jul.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes Vladimir Horowitz reply
    - Academy of American Poets, 1969-1988; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Accademia Nazionale de Santa Cecilia, 1969-1989; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Accademia Universale Guglielmo Marconi, 1990 Nov.-Dec.; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Enclosure
    - Acquarone, Pierfilippo, Emanuela, etc., 1983-1989; 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adler, Norman A., 1965 May 11-25; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes Vladimir Horowitz reply.
      See also: CBS Records
    - Afeltra, Gaetano, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Air France, 1985-1986; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Note enclosed
    - Albanese, Licia, 1990 Nov. 15; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      See also: Gimma, Joseph
    - Albright, Keith, 1988 Jun.-Oct.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alda, Frances, 1933 Dec. 30; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alder, Caine, 1974-1991; 29 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes 3 Vladimir Horowitz replies and 2 enclosures
    - Alexandre, Olivia, 1965 Nov. 11; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alexeeva, E.N., 1968-1969; 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Enclosure. See also: I.B. - Literary requests
    - Allen, Betty, 1991 Mar. 21; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allen, Woody and Mia Farrow, ca. 1989 Oct. 1; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      See also: Farrow, Mia
    - Allied Artists Agency, 1970-1984; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allin, Mort
      See: United States
    - Altschuler, Robert, 1966-1974; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders Association, Inc.
      See: Khan, Yasmin Aga, Princess
    - Amati, Anna, 1989 Nov. 8; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ambassador Foundation, 1989 Nov. 6; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Amelio, Gilbert N., 1967 Nov.-Dec.; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Airlines, 1975 Nov. 20; 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      2 seating plans and a note enclosed
    - American Cancer Society. Mercer Unit (Sharon, PA), 1969 Jul.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Federation of Musicians (Musicians' Union Locals 47 and 802), 1987-1990; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Friends of the Aldeburgh Festival, Inc., 1978 May 3-8; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Fund for Palestinian Institutions, Inc., ca. 1947 Mar.?; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American International Music Fund, Inc., 1973 Feb. 15-21; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes Vladimir Horowitz reply, 5 enclosures.
      See also: Koussevitzky, Olga (Mrs. Serge)
    - America-Israel Cultural Foundation, Inc.
      See: Mandelbaum, Bernard
    - American Liszt Society, 1968 Feb.-MAy; 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Includes 2 Vladimir Horowitz replies, 11 enclosures
    - American Music Scholarship Association, 1976 Oct.-Nov.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, 1988; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Telephone and Telegraph Company
      See: de Butts, John D.
    - Ames, Alison, 1986-1991; 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      See also: Deutsche Grammophon
    - Ames, Amyas
      See: New York Philharmonic
    - Amici della Musica, 1975 Jun.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Amstel Hotel, ca. 1986 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Anastas'eva, Margarita Viktorovna, 1984 Apr. 27; 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      7 enclosures
    - Anderson, Marian, 1928 Nov. 26; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Anderson, E. Robert, 1951 Dec. 3; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Copy of letter from John Philip Sousa, III on back
    - Anderson, Robert, 1970 Jul. 19; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Andreae, Volkmar, ca. 1933 Dec.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Angel Records
      See: Lewy, Thomas J.
    - Angeli, Guido and Corina, 1989 Nov. 19; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Angelillo, Maia and Don, ca. 1989 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Angelillo, Terry and Pat, ca. 1989 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Angeloni, Matilde de Marchi Gherini, ca. 1989 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Angyan, Thomas, 1989 Nov. 7; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Anshel, Iris Lee, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Antonini, Ferdinando, 1986-1989; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Antonova, Anna, 1989-1990; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Aoyagi, Masami
      See: Chukoron-sha, Inc.
    - [Apostoloff?], Boris, 1989 Nov. 10; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Arbasino, Alberto, ca. 1989 Nov. 10; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Architectural Digest, 1983 Apr.-May; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ardoin, John, 1965 May 5; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Argerich, Martha, 1965 May 27; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Armstead, Dennis, 1976-1987; 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes Vladimir Horowitz reply, enclosure
    - Armstrong, Peter, 1979 Jan.-Mar.; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes Vladimir Horowitz reply, 5 enclosures
    - Arndt-Condó, Erich, 1983 Dec. 2-23; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes Vladimir Horowitz reply, and Typed letter signed from Paul Fitz Gerald
    - Arrau, Claudio, 1965-1989; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arthur Rubinstein International Piano Master Competition, 1972-1973; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ascher, Barbara Lazear, 1986 Jan.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ascher, Robert C., M.D., 1989 Nov. 8; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ascher, Steven, 1978 Mar. 4; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Asher, M. Richard (Dick), 1989 Nov. 6; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      See also: PolyGram
    - Ashkenazy, Vladimir, 1965-1975; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes telegram (copy), 2 Vladimir Horowitz replies, and an enclosure
    - Asmus, Ariadna Borisovna (Mrs. Valentin Ferdinandovich), 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Association Robert Casadesus
      See: Casadesus, Gaby (Mrs. Robert)
    - Attias, Isaac, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Attordi, Gina, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Aubé, Wanda, 1965 Jun. 2; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Auer, Mrs. Leopold, 1954 Jan. 7; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Austin, Margaret, 1989 Nov. 6; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Australian Broadcasting Commission, 1968-1969; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Avedon, Richard, 1975 Jul.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Vladimir Horowitz reply and certified mail receipt
    - Avidar, Nina, 1965 Apr. 26; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Aydin, E. Tülay, 1989 Nov.-Dec.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - BMG Classics
      See: Hensler, Guenther
    - Babin, Victor (Vitya Vronsky), 1968-1989; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      See also: Cleveland Institute of Music
    - Bach-Segall, Virginia, 1989 Oct.-Nov.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bachauer, Gina and Alec, 1974 May-Jul.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bachman, David M., 1989 Nov. 6; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bachrach, Robert D., 1983 Aug.-Sep.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Backhaus, Michael, 1986 Nov. 16; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Badini, Carlo Maria, 1985-1988; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      See also: Teatro alla Scala
    - Badrutt, Andrea, 1989 Nov. 7; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Badura-Skoda, Paul, 1968-1990; 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Includes 2 Vladimir Horowitz replies
    - Bagarotti, Giovanni, 1978 Jan. 8; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bagrit, Stella, 1965-1989; 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Includes Vladimir Horowitz reply, and Typed letter signed from John Nicholls to Bagrit
    - Baka?, Vladimir, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bakaleinikov, Vladimir, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baker, Charles A., 1965-1989; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baker, Nancy, 1979 May 1; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bakst, James, 1968 Nov. 27; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baldaccini, Renza, 1989 Nov. 6; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Baldwin Piano Company, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      For original see: Bookman, Arthur and Judith
    - Balogh, Endre, 1982 Oct. 20; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      2 enclosures - includes Autograph letter signed (copy) from Henryk Szeryng "To whom it may concern."